# Colin Nebula

#### Contract

Woodbridge, ON L4L colinnebula@gmail.com +1 416 856 5764

IT Technical Support: Dealing with customers in a professional manner while tending to their technological needs efficiently, has been a mainstay in my job description for over a decade. Troubleshooting, reporting bugs, investigating, designing, and performing product tests were a daily requirements at my previous full-time job at Tira Wireless where I also gained deep insight into the development cycle of software. Currently, I provide a comprehensive array of technical services that generally involve managing issues and fixing the problem, and then addressing the root causes to implement preventative strategies for the future. Setting benchmarks, maintaining licenses, and creating guidelines are other areas I have contributed to in both my full and part-time jobs.

A recent graduate of the University of Toronto's coding Bootcamp with a new set of skills as a Full Stack Web Developer.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, React, SQL, Express.js, and Bootstrap are among some of my acquired skills.

## Work Experience

#### **Creative Director**

Nebula Media.ca - Woodbridge, ON August 2013 to September 2021

A host of responsibilities including but not limited to overseeing video production, 3D integration, and video editing.

#### **Modeler and Texture Artist**

Marvimation - Ontario July 2011 to June 2012

3D Modeling position.

Modeling objects for 3d integration through live action.

#### Internship

Intelligent Creatures 2010 to 2010

2010

Worked on MODELLING, TEXTURING, ROTO-SCOPING for feature pilot projects Rotoscoping and lens grid distortions were some of the skills that were mainly honed

## **Quality Assurance - Mobile Game Platform**

Tira Wireless - Ontario August 2007 to July 2008

- Tested and logged bugs, addressing issues through the JIRA workflow manager, conducted field tests, and regressions, developed strategies to reduce redundancies, and completed general QA duties such as running reports and assisting the team in hitting weekly targets.
- Set up a rotating schedule to improve team efficiency by assigning equipment for specific periods to each team member to reduce dead time and exceed weekly testing targets
- Clients included companies such as Sony, ING, Hudson Soft, THQ, and AccuWeather, each with specific demands and multiple unique requests to account for in testing scenarios.

## **Technical Support-Inbound Call Centre**

Epson Printing - Richmond Hill, ON December 2003 to January 2005

- Provided troubleshooting for the complete product line, resolved complaints, and ordered replacements for customers in a timely manner while up-selling other Epson products
- Conducted weekly reports, solved issues that required multi-department input, and introduced ideas such as empowering the group with more tools to resolve complaints
- Maintained top performance numbers for accuracy and commended for punctuality

## **Computer Technician**

Advanced Brake Products - Ontario June 2003 to August 2004

- Set up multiple office computers and connected them to the network to share office resources such as inventory systems, billings, production, and multiple sets of printers
- Provided considerable support in training and preparing staff for tasks on the new systems as well as set up security to prevent damage or loss of valuable information
- Performed routine tasks to keep the network and individual workstations problem-free and was responsible for all software and hardware issues experienced by staff

#### Education

## **AEC / DEP or Skilled Trade Certificate in Web Development**

University Of Toronto Coding Bootcamp - Ontario

May 2021 to November 2021

#### Skills

- Adobe After Effects
- Maya
- Adobe Illustrator
- 3D Animation
- Graphic Design
- Adobe Photoshop
- Web Design
- 3ds Max
- HTML5 (2 years)
- CSS (2 years)

- React (2 years)
- Node.js (2 years)
- Bootstrap (2 years)
- JavaScript (2 years)
- Responsive Design (2 years)
- AJAX (2 years)
- DOM (2 years)
- SQL (2 years)
- GitHub (2 years)

#### Links

http://colinnebula3dartist.blogspot.ca/

https://colinnebula.github.io/colin-react-portfolio/

## Military Service

#### **Branch: Field Artillery**

Service Country: United States

Rank: Specialist

May 1995 to May 2000

## Certifications and Licenses

### **Full Stack Web Developer**

May 2021 to Present

Creating and combining back-end and front-end web applications in a very short time frame. Using GitHub to store different versions of the project through the git workflow. Collaborating with peers through zoom to create projects under a short time constant.

#### Additional Information

Web Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, Bootstrap, Rest, MongoDB, SQL jQuery, Git Responsive Design, DOM, Node.js , Express.js, Object Relational Mapping(ORM) React, Redux

Graphic Design

SOFTWARE Maya, 3DS Max, Photoshop, After Effects, Nuke Zbrush,

Fusion, xNormal, Premiere Pro, Illustrator, PF Track.
ART Modelling and Texturing Characters, Props, and Backgrounds
ANIMATION Detailed knowledge of Animation with regard to form and
motion.

TECHNICAL Character Rigging, Lighting, and Visual Effects.

COMPOSITING Experience in Film editing and manipulation such as

Tracking and Rotoscoping using Nuke.